Before we move on let's have a quick quiz on the previous lesson to see how
you've actually understood it and the idea is you're going to fill in the
blanks on these questions. So number one is an enum is a way to define a set of
beep values, question mark values. So what is the word missing from this
particular sentence? And the answer is named value. So an enum is a way to define a
set of named values. A question two, little types restrict a variable to a
specific set of what question mark. And the answer is values. So little types
restrict a variable to a specific set of values. Question three, string enums are
more what question? Then numeric enums when debugging. So if it in the bank string
enums are more question mark than numeric enums when debugging. And the right
answer is readable. So string enums are more readable than numeric enums when
debugging. Question four, a union of literal types looks like small
medium large. This is called a what type. What's that called? It's called a
literal union type. So a union of literal types of small medium large. This is
called a literal union type. Okay, so hopefully you managed to do that. So now let's
move on to part two, which is fixing the errors. So I'm going to give you an
actual problem, and you're going to then solve it. So this is an enum, an
enum of status. And we're going to have a success. Let's have another one, which is an error.
One is pending. All right, so this is the issue. So let's current status status
equals success. Okay, so it's complaining. So you need to fix work out why
it's complaining. Perhaps give it go on the playground and then fix it. So by
hovering over it, you can see what the actual issue is that the success in a
big couple of success is not assignable to type status. So the mean status
dot success. And yes, we did. So we just need to remove this and do status dot
success. Okay, let's go for another one here. So I'm going to remove this and
let's do type. This is going to be size. And we're going to have a size of small.
The pipe size of medium pipe and large. I'm going to create a function. So let's
say create box size is up type size and console log size size size size. We're going to call
the function create box and try and call it a extra size. And of course, it's
underlined. So take a moment here, have a go on the playground and see if you
can fix this. So hovering over it, we can see we it's not recognizable because
it's not one of these three options. We can simply just remove this and do
something like large. Then the problem goes away and that's now fixed. Let's move
on and have a look at part three of our tests. And this is kind of like a bit DIY
or the order own. So what I want to do is create an enum for a weather condition.
So weather condition. Now we'll do to have three values or for sorry, all values.
Let's have sunny and let's have cloudy. That's a rainy. And let's have snowy. So if I go
it's creating an enum for this particular thing. And then also as a bonus
try and create a function that logs a message based on that condition.
Okay, let's give it a go. So enum, the weather condition. And you want the four things in here.
You want sunny, cloudy, rainy and snowy. And let's try doing a function. So let's say create
weather. Going to need to pass in the weather. Turns a bit strange, but weather condition.
And the console log. And say weather is a dollar weather.
And then call the function. So great weather. And we can do for example, weather condition
and then do whatever we want to take rainy, for example, which is always the case in UK.
And we're going to run that. And we get the weather is the numerator value of our enumeration,
say to for example, let's just change that to cloudy, run it again. And we get this here.
And let's do part four, which is about literal types. So in this challenge, I want you to
define a type called theme mode. That allows two options, a light and dark.
And then write a function. And let's call it perhaps apply theme.
Which accepts a mode and then logs that selected mode.
Okay, so we can do type. And you can call type theme mode. And this is going to have a light.
And with a pipe is also going to have a dark mode. And now we can create our function
why theme. Now we're going to pass in our mode, which was on type theme mode.
And we simply can do a console log. And say mode is dollar mode.
That's a core function apply theme. And let's pass in one of the modes.
And we say pass in, for example, light theme.
Here the log here.
And let's run it. And the mode is light.
Okay, hopefully managed to do quite well on those little tests there. And I'll see you in the next
Muchio.